The Bailey Collection
The Bailey Collection
13th century-19th century
C.7.9-C.7.43
Bailey
42 boxes
Chetham's Library
John Eglington Bailey
The antiquary, John Eglington Bailey, was born at Edgbaston, Birmingham, on 13 February 1840, the son of Charles Bailey and Mary Elizabeth Bailey, daughter of John Eglington of Ashbourne. His family removed to Lancashire during his childhood, and he was educated at Boteler’s Grammar School, Warrington, and at Owen's College, Manchester. He was employed at the counting-house of the Ralli Brothers, Manchester, where he remained until 1886.
Bailey was a prolific author: he published 420 articles, and also a number of books covering a range of subjects from Lancashire and Cheshire topography to the lives of seventeenth-century divines. He learned Pitman’s shorthand, and contributed articles to shorthand, manuscript, or lithograph magazines and bibliographical journals, such asShorthand(1882),Retrospective Review(1874), andThe Bibliographer(1882). Bailey contributed articles to newspapers and magazines such asOwen’s College Magazine(1868, 1870-1, 1878, 1880); theManchester Guardian Local Notes and Queries(1874-7); the Manchester City News Notes and Queries(1879, 1884-6); thePreston Guardian Sketches in Local History(1875-7, 1879); and theLeigh Chronicle(1878-9), amongst others. Bailey was a frequent contributor to the journals of theManchester Literary Club(1875-9, 1881-5) andManchester Field Naturalists’ Society(1878-9, 1882) as well as to various other journals, such asNotes and Queries(1864, 1869, 1873, 1874-86);Gloucestershire Notes and Queries(1879, 1881-4, 1886-8); and alsoThe Western Antiquary(1883), and the quarterly review concerned with Pagan and early-Christian antiquities,The Reliquary (1884).
His interest in the antiquities of Lancashire and Cheshire led to his contributions to a number of publications:Local Gleanings(1875, 1877-80);Cheshire Sheaf(1878-83);Lancashire and Cheshire Antiquarian Notes(1884); theJournal of the Chester Archaeological and Historic Society(1887); and theTransactions of the Lancashire and Cheshire Antiquarian Society(1886-7). His Inventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire, taken in the year A.D. 1552, was published in two parts by the Chetham Society (1879, 1888), and the final part was completed and edited by Henry Fishwick (1902). In 1881, he became the founder and editor of the monthly antiquarian magazine,The Palatine Note-Book(1881-5). He also contributed to the Encyclopaedia Britannica with articles on ‘Cryptography’ (1877) and ‘Thomas Fuller’ (1879), and also to theDictionary of National Biography(1885) with articles on a number of divines and antiquaries. Bailey also edited Henry Clarke’sThe School Candidates: A Prosaic Burlesque(Manchester, 1877), and theDiary for the years 1595-1601 of Dr John Dee, Warden of Manchester from 1595-1608(1880). He also wroteManchester al Mondo: A Contemplation of Death and Immortality(London: Pickering, 1880), and co-authored (with C.E. Banks) a biography ofColonel Alexander Rigby (Portland, Maine, USA, 1885).
However, Bailey’s life-long interest was the work of the ecclesiastical historian, Thomas Fuller (1608-61). His lecture on Fuller to the Manchester Phonographic Union, was printed in thePopular Lecturer(1864). He devoted his holidays to visiting Fuller’s places of residence, and Bailey’s most important contribution was hisLife of Thomas Fuller(Manchester: T. J. Day, 1874). His scholarship was recognised by his election as a Fellow of the Society of Antiquaries of London. Bailey had intended to issue a two-volume edition of Fuller’s sermons, but this project was never completed, and Bailey edited only one of Fuller’s sermons:A Sermon of Reformation (Manchester: T.J. Day, 1875). Bailey’s intended project was later completed and edited by W.E.A. Axon (1891). Bailey amassed a large library of antiquarian and general literature, and also collected numerous works on stenography with a view to writing a history and bibliography of English stenography, but this was another project that was never realised.
He delivered lectures to various literary and local history societies, including the Manchester Literary Club, Urmston and Flixton Literary and Scientific Society, and the Leigh Literary Society. He was also a member of the Chetham Society, serving as a councillor (1876-88) and Honorary Secretary (1882-8), as well as a councillor of the Lancashire and Cheshire Antiquarian Society (1884-9). A member of the Chorlton Road Congregational Church, he also compiled aManual of the Chorlton Road Congregational Church, Manchester (Manchester: James Andrew, 1877). From 1886, illness impaired Bailey’s research and studies, and he died, aged 48, at Etchells, Stockport, Cheshire, on 23 August 1888. He was buried at Stretford Church, Manchester, on 27 August 1888. In 1866, he had married Emma Mills, the second daughter of Samuel Mills of Ardwick, and they had four children.
Axon, W.E.A., ‘A list of the writings of John Eglington Bailey’,Transactions of the Lancashire & Cheshire Antiquarian Society, VI (1888), pp. 129-50.
‘Bailey, John Eglington (1840-88)’ (J.G. Alger, rev. Z. Lawson),The Oxford Dictionary of National Biography, ed. H.C.G. Mathew (Oxford: Oxford University Press, 2004).
Crosby, A.G.,‘A Society with No Equal’: The Chetham Society, 1843-1993, Chetham Society, 3rd ser., 37 (1993), p. 40.
Inventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire, taken in the year A.D. 1552, Part I: Salford Hundred, ed. J.E. Bailey, Chetham Society, old ser., 107 (1879).
Inventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire, taken in the year A.D. 1552, Part II: West Derby, Blackburn and Leyland Hundreds, ed. J.E. Bailey, Chetham Society, old ser., 113 (1888).
Inventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire, taken in the year A.D. 1552, Part III: Amounderness and Lonsdale Hundreds, ed. H. Fishwick, Chetham Miscellanies, new ser., 47 (1902).
Manchester Guardian, 24 Aug 1888.
Miscellaneous notes, transcripts, and original documents compiled and collected by John Eglington Bailey (1840-1888) FSA. Some of the notes are in shorthand.
There are no restrictions on access to this collection. Viewing is by prior appointment. Please contact archivist@chethams.org.uk
John Eglington Bailey’s personal library was sold by auction at Capes, Dunn & Pilcher, Manchester, from 24 to 30 June 1889, and it is not entirely clear how Chetham’s Library acquired the collection. In June 1889 the Library’s General Purposes Committee authorised the Librarian to spend up to £60 on the purchase of the Bailey manuscripts at the forthcoming sale; however, in a note in the catalogue, John Cree noted, ‘Catalogue of the Manuscripts of the late J. E. Bailey presented to the Chetham Library by R. C. Christie, Chancellor of the Diocese of Manchester’. Presumably, this note refers to Cree’s catalogue and not to the entire Bailey collection, and since there are no details of Christie's donation in the Library records, it thus appears that the Library purchased the Bailey manuscripts but was given Cree’s catalogue in the following year.
Antiquaries; Antiquarian documents; Antiquarians; Local history; Genealogy; Pedigrees; Title deeds; Letters (documents); Court rolls; Protestation returns; Shorthand; Stenography; Bailey, John Eglington. (1840-1888 ) Antiquary; Lancashire -- England; Cheshire -- England; Yorkshire -- England; Manchester -- England; Stretford -- England; Salford -- England; Flixton -- England; Chester -- England; Newton -- Cheshire -- England; Sutton -- Cheshire -- England; Sandbach -- Cheshire -- England; Nantwich -- Cheshire -- England
Shorthand; Retrospective Review; The Bibliographer; Owen’s College Magazine; Manchester Guardian Local Notes and Queries; Preston Guardian Sketches in Local History; Leigh Chronicle; Manchester Literary Club; Manchester Field Naturalists’ Society; Notes and Queries; Gloucestershire Notes and Queries; The Western Antiquary; The Reliquary
Local Gleanings; Cheshire Sheaf; Journal of the Chester Archaeological and Historic Society; Transactions of the Lancashire and Cheshire Antiquarian Society; The Palatine Note-Book; Dictionary of National Biography; The School Candidates: A Prosaic Burlesque; Diary for the years 1595-1601 of Dr John Dee, Warden of Manchester from 1595-1608; Manchester al Mondo: A Contemplation of Death and Immortality; Colonel Alexander Rigby
Popular Lecturer; Life of Thomas Fuller; A Sermon of Reformation
Manual of the Chorlton Road Congregational Church, Manchester
Transactions of the Lancashire & Cheshire Antiquarian Society
The Oxford Dictionary of National Biography
‘A Society with No Equal’: The Chetham Society, 1843-1993
Inventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire, taken in the year A.D. 1552, Part I: Salford Hundred
Inventories of goods in the churches and chapels of Lancashire, taken in the year A.D. 1552, Part III: Amounderness and Lonsdale Hundreds
Manchester Guardian
- Notes on persons and places arranged alphabetically, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9-C.7.18; GB/418/Bailey/1; 12 sub-series; Chetham's Library
  - Names and places beginning with A, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9; GB/418/Bailey/1/1; Chetham's Library
    - List of names arranged alphabetically from Adams, Thomas to Arturill, Hugh., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/1; Chetham's Library
    - Short transcript of Latin deed relating to Acton., (1286); GB/418/C.7.9 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/2; Chetham's Library
      19th century
    - Notes concerning Thomas Adams., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/3; Chetham's Library
      Extract fromBib. Ang. Theo. Vol. 1 p. 17-20, notes.
    - Notes concerning the Adlington family., (1578-1623); GB/418/C.7.9 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/4; Chetham's Library
      List of births, deaths, marriages, dates compiled by J. E. Bailey in the 19th century.
    - Letter from D. J. Northwood to J. E. Bailey concerning the Agecroft Hall muniments., 17 Jun 1885; GB/418/C.7.9 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/5; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and cuttings on Mr Harrison Ainsworth., 1885; GB/418/C.7.9 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/6; Chetham's Library
      Letter dated 13 May 1885. Pamphlet entitled 'Henry Ainsworth: His Birthplace and his Death' by Ernest Axon (Manchester, 1885), reprinted fromThe Palatine Note-Book, May 1885. Not published.
    - Pencil notes concerning John Aldern BD, vicar of the parish church of Prescott., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/7; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the Alexander family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/8; Chetham's Library
    - Allen family: notes, letters (1876, 1877 and 1885) and sketch of coat of arms., 1876-1885; GB/418/C.7.9 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/9; Chetham's Library
    - Transcript ofA Funeral Hankerchief in two parts, by Thomas Allestree, (London, 1671)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/10; Chetham's Library
      A Funeral Hankerchief in two parts
      Ink notes concerning Thomas Allestree, MA, Rector of Ashow co Warw.
    - Notes about Almanacks., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/11; 1 sheet; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from Charles W. Sutton to J. E. Bailey concerning the unknown author of theImpartial History of the Late Glorious War., 26 & 27 Sep [c 1881]; GB/418/C.7.9 no 11(i); GB/418/Bailey/1/1/12; Chetham's Library
      On verso, note by Bailey, "By John Almon, a book seller, author and editor, b in Liverpool about 1738, d 1805. An author of Numerous tracts, mostly anonymous. He is in Sutton's list".
      Letter from Hibbert Ware to J. E. Bailey concerning the above author.
    - Note: "Altrincham, Mayor or [?] 1845 June 18 iv. 6"., GB/418/C.7.9 no 12; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/13; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from [?William] Duncombe [?Pink] to J. E. Bailey requesting information on "Col Jno Alured the Regicide" or "Col Matthew Alured his relative"., 12 Mar 1884; GB/418/C.7.9 no 13; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/14; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning Alvanley near Frodsham, co Ches., (1687) & 1876; GB/418/C.7.9 no 14; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/15; Chetham's Library
      The Great Storm at Alvanley: "A true Relation of the Great Thunder, Lightning, Rain, Great Wind and Prodigious Hail that happened at Alvanley, in the Parish of Frodsham in Cheshire, on Sunday 19th June, 1687 as it was sent to a merchant in London" (Alvanley 18th July, 1687), fromThe Palatine Note-Book, 2 Jul 1883. Also cuttings and letter to J. E. Bailey from William Waddington, dated April 1876.
    - Note: "J. Ambrose's w[or]ks pub[lished] £1 6 0"., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 15; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/16; Chetham's Library
    - Letters, cuttings and notes concerning the Anderton family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 16; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/17; Chetham's Library
    - Notes, letters and a sketch pedigree of the family of Angier., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 17; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/18; Chetham's Library
      Extract from 'Life of M. Angier' relating to Ringley Chapel.
      Cutting from unknown source entitled 'Reminiscences of Dukinfield'.
      Pamphlet entitled 'Some account of the Ancient Chapel of Toxteth Park, Liverpool from the year 1618 to 1883 and of its ministers, especially of Richard Mather the first Minister' by Valentine D. David, (Liverpool, 1884).
      Some damage: handle with care.
    - Letters and notes concerning Appleton Thorn., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 18; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/19; Chetham's Library
      Letters from 1880, cutting from[?Warrington] Examiner 20 November 1880, 'Planting of the new Thorn at Appleton'; song 'Bamwing the Thorn' (to the tune of 'Bonnie Dunee') by R. E. Egerton-Warburton.
    - Note concerning James Ardern (sic) and H. Arden of Peterhouse., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 19; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/20; Chetham's Library
      Note: "Arden MSS 2 letters of Mary Wither, one to an obedient and the other to a disobedient son".
    - Note: "Arley. 3rd March 1763. Elizabeth Whitaker & John Raffald, Batchelor, married by T. Burroughs, minister"., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 20; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/21; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning Robert Armine the player, "who was intimate with Jonson & Shakespeare"., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 21; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/22; Chetham's Library
    - Note: "Arrowsmith (Father) hand 4th S X 177"., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 22; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/23; Chetham's Library
    - Note concerning John Ashbrooke of the county of Chester, clerk., 18 May 1632; GB/418/C.7.9 no 23; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/24; Chetham's Library
    - Slip of paper with note "Ascham", small amount of shorthand and a book reference., (18 May 1632); GB/418/C.7.9 no 24; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/25; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning Ashton-upon-Mersey co Ches., 17th century-19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 25; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/26; Chetham's Library
      "An account of money rec[eive]d and disbursed upon the parishe churche of Ashton towards the pulling down & repaireing the same by R. Malyn", 1715 (original manuscript).
      Notes on freeholders of Ashton-upon-Mersey AD 1685-90.
      Letter from [?Israel] J. E. Renshaw to J. E. Bailey concerning the Malyn family, 6 March 1883.
      Pamphlet: 'Some important matters for the consideration of the Electors of Ashton-upon-Mersey, being a review of the address of Mr I. S. Leadam' by D. Whittle. p. 1-13.
      "An abstract of Dr Mainwaring's and Mr Noble's title to the Advowson of the Parish & Parish Church of Ashton-upon-Mersey in the county of Chester", 1679 (original manuscript).
      Also, general notes on Ashton-upon-Mersey.
    - Ashton-upon-Lyne: [obituary] note from theGentleman's Magazine for 1800., 17th century & 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 26; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/27; Chetham's Library
      Gentleman's Magazine
      "At Ashton-under-Line, after a [?] illness, aged 17 months Julius Caesar Thompson. This was the child brought into the world by the Caesarean operation performed at the Manchester lying-in Hospital".
      Charges of Ashton, Oldham and Middleton relating to soldiers, nd [17th century] (original manuscript).
    - Letters, notes, and cuttings, concerning William, John and Henry Ashhurst., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 27; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/28; Chetham's Library
      Notes on the life of William Ashurst (sic), (17th century).
    - Cutting on Mr Henry Ashworth of Bolton., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 28; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/29; Chetham's Library
    - Pencil notes on E. Askew (born 1576)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 29; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/30; Chetham's Library
    - Pencil notes on Thomas Aspinwall of Tocksteth Park (sic), (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 30; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/31; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning Leonard Asshaw, (16th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 31; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/32; Chetham's Library
    - Notes and letters concerning William and Ralph Assheton., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 32; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/33; Chetham's Library
      Letter from Herbert A. Dobson to J. E. Bailey apologising for "not writing to acknowledge the return of the Assheton account book & Palatine Note-Book", and discusing a number of documents, 2 Oct 1884.
    - 1 sheet of notes concerning the armorial book plate of F. D. Astley of Dukinfield., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 33; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/34; 1 sheet; Chetham's Library
    - Notes concerning John Atherton and the Atherton family., 1834; GB/418/C.7.9 no 34; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/35; Chetham's Library
      Includes manuscript notes "On the must lamented death of John Atherton Esq., High Sheriff of the County Palatine of Lancaster", [1640].
      Letter from John Spencer to Mr Richard Guest, "Your information respecting Atherton has not come to hand", 18 July 1834.
    - 3 letters between John Spencer and Richard Guest relating to Atherton, a chapelry in the parish of Leigh, and the village of Chowbent, co Lancs., 1834; GB/418/C.7.9 no 35; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/36; Chetham's Library
      With notes and abstracts.
    - Notes relating to Rev Hugh Atwill, parson of St Ewe co Cornwall (d 1617)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 36; GB/418/Bailey/1/1/37; Chetham's Library
      Letter from W. P. [?Daintrey] to [?J. E. Bailey] noting references to Atwell (sic), 19 May 1885.
  - Names and places beginning with B, 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 37-45 & C.7.10 no 1-51; GB/418/Bailey/1/2; Chetham's Library
    - 2 cards addressed to J. E. Bailey., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 37; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/1; Chetham's Library
      Notice of enclosed pamphlet; letter with encosed manuscripts on Byrom.
      See also C.7.9 no. 40.
    - 2 letters from Francis M. Jackson to J. E. Bailey., 1885; GB/418/C.7.9 no 38; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/2; Chetham's Library
      1 concerning the library of Sir Richard Baker, 6 Nov 1885, and the other asking a question about Baker's identity, 29 Oct 1885.
    - Printed case between "Thomas Lord Bishop of Ely, Plaintiff in Error [and] Richard Bentley, DD Master of Trinity College, Cambridge, Defendant in error...To be heard at the Bar of the House of Lords"., 1732; GB/418/C.7.9 no 39; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/3; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from John Byrom to Mr John Stansfield, with postscript from Thomas Bentley, apparently concerning the printing [?of a book]., 19 Feb [?1719]; GB/418/C.7.9 no 40; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/4; Chetham's Library
      Printed inChetham Society NS no 70, pp 167-8.
    - Cuttings, notes and letters relating to Pietro Vannes, rector, and William Brereton, Lord of the Manor of Longdendale, (16th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 no 41; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/5; Chetham's Library
    - Isaac Hawkins Browne,De Animi Immortalitate. Poema (imprint Hamburg)., 1754; GB/418/C.7.9 no 42; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/6; Chetham's Library
      De Animi Immortalitate. Poema
      Erased signature not Byrom's.
    - Isaac Hawkins Brown,A Poem on the Immortality of the Soul, translated from the Latin by J. Cranwell, MA, Cambridge., 1765; GB/418/C.7.9 no 43; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/7; Chetham's Library
      Printed by J. Bentham, printer to the university; for R. Matthews, bookseller in Cambridge; sold by J. Rivington, A. Millar, T. Payne, London; and J. Fletcher in Oxford.
    - Notes and pamphlets concerning John Byrom., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.9 nos 44 & 45; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/8; Chetham's Library
      No 45 includes "Byrom's 'Three Black Crows'...A paper read before the Manchester Literary Club" by John Evans (Manchester, 1882), reprinted from theManchester Quarterly No. 1 (January 1882).
      Also 'Byrom and the Wesleys' by Rev Elijah Hoole (London: William Nichols, 1864), reprinted from theWesleyan-Methodist Magazine. With Byrom portrait.
      See also number 40 above. For Byrom material see Bailey Sale Catalogue p. 250 lot 2438.
    - A list of names from Baker to Byrom., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 1; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/9; Chetham's Library
    - Letter from W. Beaumont to J. E. Bailey concerning Dr Philip Baker., 11 Feb 1885; GB/418/C.7.10 no 2; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/10; Chetham's Library
    - Notes headed "Memoirs of Dr Walter Balcangual Dean of Durham who died Dec 25 1645"., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 3; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/11; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on the Baldwin family, and "Prayers by the late Mr Baldwin of Manchester in the County of Lancaster, Gent, 1767"., GB/418/C.7.10 no 4; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/12; Chetham's Library
      Original MS, fragile and damaged.
    - Copies of printed ballads., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 5; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/13; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on Rev Humphrey and Rev Nehemiah Barnett, (17th century)., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 6; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/14; Chetham's Library
    - An account of the Lancashire custom of "barring out at school"., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 7; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/15; Chetham's Library
    - Papers concerning Thomas Barritt., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 8; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/16; Chetham's Library
      2 letters from Thomas Gibbons (correspondent for English and American newspapers) to J. E. Bailey regarding a portrait of Barritt, 27 Feb & 10 Apr 1883.
      'A Heraldic Poem' by Thomas Barritt.
      Proof portrait of Barritt.
    - Notes on the history of Barton-on-Irwell and the meaning of the place name., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 9; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/17; Chetham's Library
    - Letters and notes concerning the Barton family., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 10; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/18; Chetham's Library
      Extracts from the District Registry attached to the Probate Division of Her Majesty's Court of Justice at Chester, concerning Robert Barton.
      "Answers to interrogations concerning the death of Robert Barton of Smithells. 1580".
    - Waste book of George Baycliffe of Leeds (died 1756), with entries relating to Lancashire., 18th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 11; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/19; Chetham's Library
    - Notes on Edward Baynard'sHealth, a Poem., (1749); GB/418/C.7.10 no 12; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/20; Chetham's Library
      Health, a Poem
    - Notes on Rev Thomas Bedford., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 13; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/21; Chetham's Library
      Letter from J. [?Fugh] Dredge to J. E. Bailey, with copy of Bedford's will dated 16 Feb 1651, 8 Mar 1882.
    - Extract from Lancashire and Cheshire Antiquarian Notes concerning the Belfield family of Poulton., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 14; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/22; Chetham's Library
    - Letters and notes concerning Belfield Hall and a picture found there., 1884; GB/418/C.7.10 no 15; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/23; Chetham's Library
      With cutting from theRochdale Times, "Disputed ownership of a picture", 22 Mar 1884.
    - Collections of notes, letters etc on persons named Bell., 19th century; GB/418/C.7.10 no 16; GB/418/Bailey/1/2/24; Chetham's Library